<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>open-data | Satellite Report</title>
    <link>/tag/open-data/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/open-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>open-data</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>open-data</title>
      <link>/tag/open-data/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>First CEEMID Regional Open Data Release</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internet use: participating in social networks (creating user profile, posting messages or other contributions to facebook, twitter, etc.) [percentage of individuals]&lt;/em&gt; shows the development of social media use in the past 10 years in very high detail.  Social media is one of the most important ways to communicate with fans and find audiences for gigs, performances and to share new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/internet_use_social_networks.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Social media use 2011-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chosen dataset is highlighting several new priorities of CEEMID.  This indicator, which is based on a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsso.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/nui/show.do?dataset=isoc_r_iuse_i&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurostat statistical product&lt;/a&gt;, has a much higher data quality than the Eurostat release, it is easier to use, and goes beyond the detail of national statistics.  It contains data on 411 territories in Europe, including countries, provinces and smaller regions, even some metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is available on the European open research data repository, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/3754574#.XpimX8gzbIU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be updated annually. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3754574&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.3754574.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing information is available in the dataset.  First, we have used our open source software to correct the regional boundary changes during the decade (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/&#34;&gt;Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data was missing in the end of the dataset, we used the last observation carry forward, when in the beginning, the next observation carry backwards data.  Gaps in the data were interpolated using linear interpolation. Whenever data was available on a larger (provincial level), we imputed it to the smaller regional units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data contains standard national / regional references according the European NUTS2013 standard for backwards compatibility. Further documentation will be available on our methodology on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation.ceemid.eu&lt;/a&gt; wiki website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, the data was put into a table that complies with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidy data&lt;/a&gt; principles for easier processing on computers and immediate use in spreadsheet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_238711_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_246037_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_250355_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247818_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247520_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_243997_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Reporting</title>
      <link>/project/reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/reporting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;reproducible reports&lt;/strong&gt; are automated, self-refreshing documents, that contain data pipelines to the original data sources, the analytical code and the narrative assessment in a single file.  These reports are saving potentally thousands of error-prone human working during the compilation of very complex technical documentations, such as regulatory filings or complex research documentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they are retrieving the latest available data from the Client&amp;rsquo;s internal systems and from external data sources, they can be re-freshed daily, weekly, monthly or annually. The program is refreshing the data visualizatoin, the data tables, the data citations and bibliography, and they re-create the statistical and descriptive technical annexes at every compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-of-reproducible-reporting&#34;&gt;Advantages of reproducible reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reproducible report allows independent assessment and duplication of the programmatic results. This is a guarantee of high quality and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviewability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our application’s results are can be assessed and judged by our user’s experts, or experts they trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducibility&lt;/strong&gt; means that we are providing data products and tools that allow the exact duplication of our results during assessments.  This makes sure that all logical steps can be verified. Reproducibility ensures that there is no lock-in to our applications. You can always chose a different data and software vendor, or compare our results with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are creating applications that are confirmable and auditable. These are usually required by the ethical guidelines and professional standards of our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmability&lt;/strong&gt; means that using our applications findings leads to the same professional results as other available software and information. Our data products use the open-source statistical programming language R. We provide details about our algorithms and methodology to confirm our results in SPSS or Stata or sometimes even in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auditability&lt;/strong&gt; means that our data and software is archived in a way that external auditors can later review, reproduce and confirm our findings.  This is a &lt;em&gt;stricter form of data retention&lt;/em&gt; that most organizations apply, because we do not only archive results step-by-step but all computational steps – as if your colleagues would not only save every step in Excel but also their keystrokes. While auditability is a requirement in accounting, but we are extending this approach to all the quantiative work of a professional organization in an advisory or consulting capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because our data applications are confirmable and auditable, they are the best suited to meet the internal or external regulatory compliance of organizations, for example, reporting to external regulators or supervisory boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internationalization-and-localization&#34;&gt;Internationalization And Localization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the tables, visualizations, citations and repeating technical documentations are created programatically, they are ideally suited for multi-language environments. Our reproducible research reports are capable of creating a master (English or generic) report and the skeletons of translations with translated and well-placed, translated illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/ceereport_2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Central &amp;amp; Eastern European Music Industry Report 2020&lt;/a&gt; is based on our data collection in 12 countries. Every visualization and data cited in the report is programatically created, and can be refreshed or translated automatically. It was 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/post/2020-01-30-ceereport/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;presented&lt;/a&gt; as a good case-study on national and comparative evidence-based policymaking in the cultural and creative sector on the CCS Ecosystems: FLIPPING THE ODDS Conference – a two-day high-level stakeholder event jointly organized by Geothe-Institute and the DG Education and Culture of the European Commission with the Creative FLIP project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploiting Open Data</title>
      <link>/project/open_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/open_data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Europe, municipalities, state authorities, governments, and the EU itself are creating vast data assets to serve various public needs.  Since 2003 the EU and its members states have theoretically opened these vast data resources for the re-use of the market sector when there are no privacy or national security concerns present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right after the opening of these data assets, it was estimated that the value of re-used public sector data, for example geographical, company registry, court, transport infrastructure data is around 25-47 billion euros. In the last 15 years, there have been signficant new investments into data assets, and futher innovation on using data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, the re-usable public data offers a consistent and cheap alternative to private data collection, for example, pan-European surveying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-of-psi&#34;&gt;Advantages of PSI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are vast data assets available for marginal cost, or for free, in size and value that could not be profitably financed by the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-use of taxpayer funded research increases the value for tax money, and avoids unnecessary duplication of data investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to collect past data in the present. Public sources, however, often contain hidden data going back for 10-20 years or even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;difficulties-of-psi&#34;&gt;Difficulties of PSI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-usable data was created for a different purpose. While the data may be of high quality, it is likely not to be processed in the form the re-user wants to see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is often not documented, or not documented for the purpose of re-use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is often difficult to find.  It is technically re-usable, but even its existence is unknown for most business users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direct data costs of PSI are usually low - users only have to pay marginal costs, or sometimes they are not charged for a fair use of the data. However, the data processing costs are significant, because the data was not prepared for the business users needs.  The data processing requires a special understanding of statistical standards and public data. This is one of our specialities - besides having a very detailed &amp;lsquo;treasure map&amp;rsquo; of European PSI.  We are creating thousands of high-quality, pan-European business and policy indicators from open data sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-background&#34;&gt;Legal Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the EU, open data is governed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?qid=1561563110433&amp;amp;uri=CELEX:32019L1024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Directive on open data and the re-use of public sector information - in short: Open Data Directive (EU) 2019/1024&lt;/a&gt;. It entered into force on 16 July 2019. It replaces the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32003L0098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Public Sector Information Directive&lt;/a&gt;, also known as the ‘PSI Directive’ which dated from 2003 and was subsequently amended in 2013. The founder of CEEMID, Daniel Antal has been involved in Open Data and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/publication/hungary_psi_2009/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PSI since 2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
