<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Antal, CFA | Satellite Report</title>
    <link>/author/daniel-antal-cfa/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/daniel-antal-cfa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Daniel Antal, CFA</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 15:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Daniel Antal, CFA</title>
      <link>/author/daniel-antal-cfa/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase The Value Of Market Research With Open Data And Survey Harmonization</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-07-10-retroharmonize/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last weeks I have been releasing the early source code of two R packages, 
&lt;a href=&#34;publication/retroharmonize_2020/&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; harmonization infrastructure of surveys, and  
&lt;a href=&#34;publication/eurobarometer_2020/&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; for Eurobarometer-specific work, complemented by my earlier release of 
&lt;a href=&#34;publication/regions_2020/&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks about 20,000 regional boundary changes of French departments, Polish voivodeships and Hungarian counties, and other sub-national divisions of about 32 European countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very techincal terms of &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; , &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; or retrospective harmonization hide opportunities that can significantly increase the value for money in empirical market research, potentially increasing the value of a high-cost, high-value survey to multiple times of its euro value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my work, I have used &lt;em&gt;ex ante&lt;/em&gt; harmonized questionnaires with EU survey programs, for example, the harmonized CAP surveys to determine the characteristics of concert audiences in a country, or people who download music to their computers.  The EU has been opening up its own survey programs in a piecemeal fashion, and surveys used by the European Commission, the Parliament, or even the national statistical offices are becoming more and more available.  After harmonizing the questions, I can apply &lt;em&gt;ex post&lt;/em&gt; harmonization of the results, too, resulting in a far more valuable research document:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can usually compare the basic values, such as concert visiting likelihood in the past – for example, I surveyed Hungary and Slovakia first in 2015, but immediately could compare with 2013 and 2007 data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/gif/concert_hu_animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions over time&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I get international benchmarks for free, for example, German, Czech, French data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cee_concert_demography_15x10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Harmonized concert visiting questions accross countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the hierarchical nature of CAP surveys, I can make reasonable estimates of details that I survey only in one or few countries, such as visiting jazz concerts, and not concert only; or copying non-licensed music to devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there is no free lunch here.  I can access millions of euros values of survey data, but nobody will make prepare it for my use. These surveys were processed for different users and different uses and joining them with my data is a very difficult task that I had been doing better and better in the past 5 years. To make this work as error-free as possible, I will publish the critical elements of the code as open source software on CRAN soon - the github release is an early version of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the current momentum is due to a new contributor to these packages, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://martakolczynska.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marta Kołczyńska&lt;/a&gt;, who is an excellent R programmer and a bright academic in international survey harmonization and reproducible research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;related&#34;&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the  
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;retroharmonize&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://eurobarometer.danielantal.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eurobarometer&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://regions.danielantal.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First CEEMID Regional Open Data Release</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 17:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internet use: participating in social networks (creating user profile, posting messages or other contributions to facebook, twitter, etc.) [percentage of individuals]&lt;/em&gt; shows the development of social media use in the past 10 years in very high detail.  Social media is one of the most important ways to communicate with fans and find audiences for gigs, performances and to share new releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/dataanimation/internet_use_social_networks.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Social media use 2011-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chosen dataset is highlighting several new priorities of CEEMID.  This indicator, which is based on a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://appsso.eurostat.ec.europa.eu/nui/show.do?dataset=isoc_r_iuse_i&amp;amp;lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eurostat statistical product&lt;/a&gt;, has a much higher data quality than the Eurostat release, it is easier to use, and goes beyond the detail of national statistics.  It contains data on 411 territories in Europe, including countries, provinces and smaller regions, even some metropolitan areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dataset is available on the European open research data repository, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/record/3754574#.XpimX8gzbIU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Zenodo&lt;/a&gt;. It will be updated annually. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3754574&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.3754574.svg&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The processing information is available in the dataset.  First, we have used our open source software to correct the regional boundary changes during the decade (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/2020-02-13-regional_eurostat/&#34;&gt;Programatic Approach To Work With European Regional Data Panels&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data was missing in the end of the dataset, we used the last observation carry forward, when in the beginning, the next observation carry backwards data.  Gaps in the data were interpolated using linear interpolation. Whenever data was available on a larger (provincial level), we imputed it to the smaller regional units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data contains standard national / regional references according the European NUTS2013 standard for backwards compatibility. Further documentation will be available on our methodology on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.ceemid.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation.ceemid.eu&lt;/a&gt; wiki website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last, the data was put into a table that complies with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v059i10&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tidy data&lt;/a&gt; principles for easier processing on computers and immediate use in spreadsheet applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_238711_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_246037_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Internet use: participating in social networks (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_250355_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2011)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2011_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247818_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2015)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2015_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_247520_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;CEEMID metadata summary (2019)&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-16-regional-opendata-release/gallery/metadata_ceemid_regional_social_media_use_2019_hua485aaf22d1f04af04808580e8565870_243997_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Social Distancing in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People around the world are facing newer and newer exponential charts everyday. We’re all hoping for new information about the progress against the coronavirus. Unfortunately, the vast majority of these charts is meaningless. In fact, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/coronavirus-case-counts-are-meaningless/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;coronavirus case counts are meaningless&lt;/a&gt;, unless they are done with very heavy statistical knowledge, and even then they are very messy. Countries have different testing and hospitalization protocols, death certificating standards, and there are less and more trustworthy governments. We do not really know the severity of the local epidemics and the relative success of public health policies.&lt;/p&gt;








  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/countryclusters.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Clustering countries on current lockdown strictness and change&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/countryclusters_huc63f6ee1cc1b69a8e28d2c9e7295fd18_347025_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;338&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/difference_summary_en.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Changes in community space use, end of March and early April&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/difference_summary_en_huc7370673eb468102ac3ad5af70997f54_262570_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
      
        
      
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-gallery&#34; href=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/work_home_change_EN.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Growth in time spend at home and in the workplace since January&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img data-src=&#34;/post/2020-04-15-comparing-social-distancing/gallery/work_home_change_EN_huf1bc5f0534491039237e4dc526b79bf4_336010_0x190_resize_q90_lanczos.jpg&#34; class=&#34;lazyload&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;263&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we have some timely information on how people and the economy react to the epidemic, because there are ongoing, frequent, and comparable data sources on various consequences of the epidemic.  A particularly interesting big data source is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blog.google/technology/health/covid-19-community-mobility-reports/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google’s geolocational reporting&lt;/a&gt; on how people’s time spent in homes, workplaces, parks, shopping areas and recreational areas change. Google gets plenty of realtime data from hundreds of millions of people and compares them by days in the week and local time with the ‘baseline’ scenario before the outbreak of the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the locational data of various smartphones and application data, we know that people spend 10-15% more time at home since January, and 40-50% less in their workplaces.  Similar data is available for other locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/work_home_en_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stay at home or go to the workplace?&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While people are spending less time in the workplace and more at home in every European country, there are significant differences.  Countries in the top left corner, most notable Sweden, switched less from workplaces to homes.  On the bottom right corner, Spain and Italy, which were most hit by the epidemic, are in the most severe form of lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some outliers, like Romania, where people stay a lot more at home, but not so much less in the workplaces – probably they cannot afford to stay clear of the job, but they are reducing other activities.  Or, in the case of Germany, people spend a lot more time in parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/difference_summary_en_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Differences in space use in Europe&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grouped the countries according to their dynamics.  Looking at Belgium and Luxembourg, we see that they are more locked down than the typical European country, but they are moving up in the first week of April compared to the last week of March. This is very much in line with their improving strain on the health system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/post/2020-04-15-covid/countryclusters_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clusters of countries&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is worrying is that there appears to be a significant asynchronicity in the Schengen zone, where people and goods should move around freely.  The peripheric countries, which are less densely populated, often less integrated into the global transport and travel routes, are getting into the local epidemics later, and are acting later.  This is logical from a national point of view, but given that the European economy is very much integrated, it will prolong the pain.  The Netherlands, France and Germany need plenty of seasonal agricultural workers from the Southeast, where the lockdown is just getting really strict.  While some of their regions see improving national epidemic situations, the easing will increase the intensity of the local epidemic if a large number of workers will arrive from countries that are just going into the epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The efficient solution, as many public health officials keep saying, would be a synchronized effort to contain the virus.  The different pace and strictness of social distancing measures will mean that the local epidemics will not be in synchronization, and the countries will re-infect each other, this way prolonging the economic and social cost of this devastating pandemic.  While health policy is a national competence in the European Union, in fact, the European economic and social life is so much integrated, not only within the Schengen Zone, but even with future, prospective and candidate members states in the Balkans, that a far more coordinated public health policy would be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use this in your article? Further research? Collaboration? The data &amp;amp; code is available in a private github repo. Let&amp;rsquo;s get in touch on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/antaldaniel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/antaldaniel&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or via 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://danielantal.eu/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;danielantal.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please quote this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antal, Daniel (2020): Comparing Social Distancing in Europe (March, April 2020). figshare. Preprint. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.12124194.v1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
